[theme music playing]
[Ivy] I'll make them pay.
Hello, Poblacion Ardiente. I'm back.
Who is she?
[Pandoy] Our champion, Diego Ardiente…
It's Diego, my best friend.
-Yes?
-For you.
Thank you.
[Julio] That's where
your interest lies. Rolling in mud.
Like I told you once before,
some people are only
meant to be worker ants.
I guess that's all you are.
[Diego] I think it's better.
At least one Ardiente
can stand with the people.
[Dante] I want you to learn
how to protect yourself
because your Mom and I
won't always be by your side.
I promise, I will not leave this town
until I find out why this happened.
[Diego] I know Lily will
come back someday. I can feel it.
She'll come back.
[Ivy] Emilia is the key
to what happened to Mom.
But you? You are the key to Emilia.
I'll start with you.
[tense music playing]
[gunshots nearby]
Hold it. Relax, I won't do anything.
Looks like you wasted a bullet.
Didn't capture anything?
Bad day, I guess.
[scoffs]
Do you know you're trespassing?
This is private property.
You're a new face.
I know everyone who lives in my town.
I'm Mayor Arnaldo Ardiente-Torillo.
Wow.
Mr. Mayor Arnaldo Ardiente-Torillo.
[scoffs]
I guess it's not a bad day.
I spotted the right person
who can guide me in this little town.
Mr. Mayor, my name is Ivy.
Ivy Aguas.
[tense music playing]
Mr. Mayor, I saw on your
website that you're looking for investors.
But other than this forest for hunting,
I don't see any exceptional opportunities.
That's pretty blunt.
No mayor wants to hear things like that.
Oh, I'm sorry, Mr. Mayor,
but I call it as I see it.
Maybe you need to look closer.
Ms. Ivy Aguas, let me show you around.
Maybe I can change
how you look at my little town.
We'll see, Mr. Mayor.
Well, I have to go. Happy hunting.
[action music playing]
Sweetie! Where have you been all day?
When I woke up, you were gone.
What happened?
Nanny, have you eaten yet?
Get dressed, and let's eat.
Where have you been?
Nanny Carlotta.
I've laid the trap.
All we need is for him
to walk right into it.
I'm sure that Mayor Ardiente
will be here tomorrow.
And when that happens, I must be ready.
Let's go.
Dear…
Here, Mayor.
[action music playing]
That's all the information
I got as of now.
But if we look at the status
of her assets,
she can be an investor here in Ardiente.
Good work. You're very reliable.
[upbeat music playing]
[upbeat music continues playing]
I knew I'd find you here.
Mr. Mayor.
What brings you here?
I wanted to change
your perception of Ardiente.
Oh, no. It might be hard.
Please…
Humor me. You're here, anyway.
Let me give you the grand tour.
After that, if you're still not convinced…
at least, you can say…
you tried.
No regrets.
Now you're making it hard
for me, Mr. Mayor.
[Ivy] Oops.
[Arnaldo] Please, let me.
[upbeat music playing]
[Ivy] Mr. Mayor.
You didn't have to fetch me.
I have my own car, and I can drive.
I know. But where's the fun in that?
This is Madrigal.
He's my most trusted man.
He'll accompany us.
Just him?
You don't have
any other bodyguards besides him?
Well, we don't need that many
bodyguards where we're going.
And if I need to, I can protect you.
Shall we?
[upbeat music playing]
[Arnaldo] Um…
The first stop is the school
that our family built.
We're still expanding the building
so we can take in more students.
This hospital
is one of the highlights of the town.
An Ardiente was the one
who had it built too.
My grandfather, actually.
We're well-equipped enough
that we can compete
with the hospitals in Manila.
Oh. Check that out. That one right there.
-What? What's--
-That. That church.
Mr. Mayor, I didn't know we were close.
Sorry.
Ivy. See that? That statue.
That's my grandfather.
I remember there was a feast
when it was erected.
I was still a kid.
As long as this statue
stands firm in our town,
you will continue to have
honest service and leadership!
-[Julio] Viva Ardiente!
-[crowd] Viva Ardiente!
Who's that man?
Oh, him? He was already like that
when I came back from studying in America.
They say he just went mad one day
and began living on the streets.
He doesn't have a family.
They say he disappears from time to time.
Then suddenly shows up again at the plaza.
It was him! Him!
-Him!
-He'll leave town and then come back.
But don't worry. He's harmless.
-He's pure evil!
-[woman] Hey, nutcase!
-[woman exclaims] Move along!
-You go away!
[wailing]
Let's go, Madrigal.
[Arthur] No! No! Stop!
Wait!
Okay, I'm gonna show you everything.
Or you might say I'm biased
because I just showed you
the nice parts of the town.
You know… I was thinking.
For a mayor, you've got lots of free time.
I cleared my schedule for you.
[upbeat music playing]
[Ivy laughing]
Mr. Mayor, I didn't expect you
to be such a comedian.
I have my moments.
[Loring] Get an inventory
of those vegetables!
Don't forget the prices!
We have to… Okay, good.
[Diego] Here, sir.
[Loring] Yes. Shouldn't that
be shipped already?
-Here.
-Are we almost done?
-Yeah.
-We're almost done.
Sir, how are you holding up?
Are you still okay?
-Why wouldn't I be? We're both fit!
-[Diego chuckles]
You? I don't see any muscles!
You're getting pale!
You need fresh air!
You need to build some muscle!
Build some muscle? Come here!
I'll show you some muscle!
[Loring laughs]
You missed this, didn't you?
See? You're wrong!
-It's Arnaldo!
-What?
We're here. Mayor.
[suspenseful music playing]
Mayor.
May I talk to you for a while?
Okay.
-Excuse me.
-Sure.
-Why?
-I need to leave for a bit, Mayor.
-Where are you going?
-I need to take care
of the property
you want to show our guest.
Okay, we can't afford
to make any mistakes.
Yes, Mayor.
[man] Because it's cold
in the office and in the car.
Thank you.
-[man] Who's that?
-[Loring] Oh.
["Sa'Yo" instrumental playing]
[Loring] Oh.
-It's her…
-Oh, yeah.
[Arnaldo] Let's go?
-Diego has a huge crush on her.
-Oh…
Let's go?
Yeah.
[Loring] She was the woman
I told you about before.
Let's welcome them!
[Arnaldo] Good day!
-Good morning!
-Mayor!
-Mayor.
-Good day, Mayor!
Nice to see you here today.
Yes, I'm just showing our guest
around Ardiente.
I want her to see
all the beautiful places in this town.
And above all, I want her
to meet all you hardworking people.
They are the cooperative of the workers
and farmers of this town.
This is Mr. Fernan.
-Good morning.
-He leads this group.
Along with Mr. Pandoy and Mrs. Loring.
And this is my brother, Diego.
He helped Mr. Pandoy
form this cooperative.
["Sa'Yo" instrumental playing]
Diego.
Ivy Aguas.
[clears throat]
What are you doing here, Diego?
I'm always here… helping the people.
Ivy! So that's your name.
-Mr. Pandoy.
-Yes, it's Mr. Pandoy. Uh…
We've been wondering
who the beautiful tourist was.
[stutters] You've met?
[Loring] Oh…
Mayor, I was trying
to sell her some fritters,
but she told me she's on a diet.
-[Pandoy laughs]
-[Loring] Right?
But, ma'am, I didn't cook some today.
I'm afraid you won't be able to try them.
[Pandoy] Too bad! My Loring
cooks the best fritters!
Maybe next time.
Sorry, Mayor, I didn't cook today.
I didn't know you were coming.
Oh, that's all right. Like what Ivy said,
we can try it next time.
We won't stay long here anyway.
We still have other places to see.
So, we'll be on our way!
-Thanks for dropping by.
-All right.
-Thank you, Mayor!
-Nice meeting you all.
-You too.
[Pandoy] Ms. Ivy…
-[Loring] Enjoy your stay!
-Let's go.
COOPERATIVE OF FARMERS
AND WORKERS OF ARDIENTE
So that pretty woman is the Mayor's guest!
[Pandoy chuckles]
But I don't think the Mayor
knows about the flowers
you gave at the tournament.
Right, Diego?
[Pandoy chuckles]
So, where are you
taking me next, Mr. Mayor?
The next place we're going to
has something you can only find
in this region of the country.
Let's see.
["Sa'Yo" by Silent Sanctuary playing]
[tense music playing]
[Ivy] So…
Why are we here?
Well… My grandfather…
Congressman Julio Ardiente…
had these windmills installed.
In this region, this is the only town
that can generate its own electricity.
If the region has a blackout,
it won't affect Poblacion.
And now…
we all know…
renewable energy is big these days.
So…
Impressed yet?
Wow!
Wow.
That was my best shot!
Those?
I already saw those when I arrived.
Mr. Mayor, I thought…
you wanted to change
my opinion of this town?
Of your town.
Are you giving up?
Oh, Ms. Aguas.
I don't easily give up.
So, if I really can't convince you…
can we just enjoy the rest of the day?
I guess so.
Well then…
[Arnaldo chuckles]
Mr. Mayor, I thought you were
looking for investors.
If you want to go on a date
with me, you could've just asked.
I'm a hunter.
I like hitting two birds with one stone.
[chuckles]
[exhales]
[suspenseful music playing]
Whose house is that?
I said… Whose house is that?
[upbeat music playing]
I already paid
the reservation fee for this house.
But I can get a refund.
You can have this property.
If you want it.
And it comes with the lake.
[Arnaldo exhales]
[chuckles]
I get it. You planned this.
This was the clincher
of your sales pitch for Ardiente.
Fine. I'll admit.
I did my research on you.
I discovered
you have an eye for real estate.
I also learned you don't back down
if a property catches your eye.
And this house…
Let's just say I had
a feeling you'd love it.
I figured, if I can't
convince you to invest in Ardiente…
Well, I can at least give you a reason
to come back every now and then.
Which you will do
if you end up purchasing this house.
You're starting to impress me, Mr. Mayor.
You're giving me reasons…
Reasons to keep coming back here.
So, what will it take, Mr. Mayor, to…
make this property mine?
I want you…
to invest here in Ardiente.
I'm planning to build
an export processing zone…
on the property we visited earlier.
You're complicating things, Mr. Mayor.
Well, you know what they say.
If you want something,
you should know how to get it.
Do we have a deal?
[tense music playing]
You know I want that property badly!
Even if it's just sitting
there waiting for us to take it,
I want that property!
Mom, that property is useless to us!
What do you want it for?
We're not moving out anyway.
That's not my point!
My point is I want that house!
It's our house! It's mine! All mine!
Grandpa.
[tense music playing]
[Ivy] Nanny Carlotta…
that house was previously owned
by their political rival.
But the family went bankrupt.
And now they're living abroad.
Same old story. That's how
things work around here.
-Careful, it's hot.
-Thank you.
[Arnaldo] That property is worthless.
Now, what is the reason
why we can't acquire it
in the first place?
We lack funds. All our funds
are allocated for the campaign.
Now think about this.
By sacrificing that property,
we can generate another stream of income.
[Carlotta] When will you move in?
As soon as possible.
As you know, the Ardientes
are strapped for cash.
[chuckles]
I'm sure the mayor
will give me what I want.
-But--
-Arnaldo's right.
We should give up that property.
But as usual, all you ever
care about is spending money.
Arnaldo.
Yours is the right decision.
[Ivy] I told you. I can handle this.
[tense music playing]
[upbeat music playing]
[Carlotta] It's so beautiful!
Look at the pool.
[chuckles]
Oh, sweetie.
I called the servants in Manila.
They'll be here soon.
-Thanks, Nanny.
-I'll check the kitchen.
-Okay.
-Are you hungry?
I'm fine. I still have a call to make.
[Carlotta] Okay.
[line ringing]
Yes, Joan? Please deliver the documents
I have to sign here at Poblacion Ardiente.
Just use one of the company cars.
And, um, tell Mr. Sy
I will return his call in an hour.
All right. Thank you.
[pensive music playing]
[sighs]
[Prianka] Always remember this.
Being a woman is both
a blessing and a curse.
It's a double-edged sword, Ivy.
Should you use your femininity
to your advantage,
make sure not to hurt yourself.
You're Ivy Aguas.
To the world, you are my daughter.
You are the heiress to everything I own.
But while I'm still breathing,
I'll make sure
that you learn and earn
to deserve every cent.
You shouldn't just be beautiful.
You should also be tough. Smart.
And your heart should be
in the right place.
If you can't do that,
you'll be back on the streets.
Do you understand me?
Yes, Ms. Prianka.
Beautiful.
[phone ringing]
-Mr. Mayor.
-Dinner.
At my place this weekend.
With the family.
Dinner?
With the family?
Isn't that too fast?
Uh, well, not really.
Because you still call me Mr. Mayor.
When will you call me by my name?
Perhaps…
when I get to know your whole family.
Oh!
Does that mean it's a yes?
Yes, to dinner.
[scoffs]
See you, Mr. Mayor.
[Ivy] I replied to Mr. Teodoro.
I said, "no deal".
I also emailed everyone.
I told them not to entertain him
until he agrees to my terms.
-Joan? Joan!
-Yes, ma'am?
You know what to do.
Yes, ma'am. Noted.
By the way, I brought
everything you need from work.
Okay, thank you.
It's late, you should get going.
You still have to go back to Manila.
I'll just see you next week. Take care.
Yes, Ms. Aguas. Thank you.
[suspenseful music playing]
Sweetie? I prepared some snacks for you.
Thanks, Nanny.
Sweetie?
I'm sure the rest of that family
knows you're here now.
Have they gotten in touch?
Yes, Nanny.
They know.
And tonight…
Ivy Aguas will introduce herself
to the Ardientes.
[chuckles]
How exciting.
[suspenseful music playing]
[Diego] Nanny… Here are the vegetables.
[Loring] Okay. Just put them there.
You know what?
I think Ms. Ivy will be
staying here much longer.
I thought she'd just turn
the mansion she bought
into a vacation house.
But some men went there the other day.
Actually, she's at our house
right now. Arnaldo invited her.
Apparently, it's to formally
welcome her to Ardiente.
Why are you here if she's there?
What? What would I do there?
Oh, come on. Don't you like that Ivy?
Are you going to let
your brother make a move on her?
[Loring] Well, if that woman
is interested in Arnaldo,
then she's not the one for Diego.
You know what, Nanny?
You're right. I should've
given you those flowers.
[Pandoy chuckling]
I knew it! You finally regret it.
But don't worry, dear. I love you.
With all my heart. [giggling]
You know that.
[tense music playing]
This way, Ms. Aguas.
Uh… I'll let them know you're here now.
Thank you.
[dramatic music playing]
[Ivy] I'll find out the truth
about what you had to do
with my mother's death.
[dramatic music playing]
Hi. You must be Ivy.
Yes.
Ivy Aguas.
Governor Emilia Ardiente.
Pleased to meet you.
So, how is your newly acquired property?
Do you know I've been eyeing that house?
What made you give it up, Governor?
Arnaldo convinced me to let you have it.
Awww.
I admire people like you, Governor.
Those who know how to accept defeat.
But I never lose when it matters.
Never? So, this was your first time?
[tense music playing]
Ivy.
-Mr. Mayor.
-Good evening.
You look lovely.
-Hmm. Thank you.
-Well, I can see you met
my mom already. Mom, where's Dad?
-On his way.
-Okay, good.
Grandpa's on his way too.
Shall we wait for them in the dining room?
-Sure.
-Okay, let's go. Shall we?
-Oh. Mom. Coming?
-Sure.
[Julio] Arnaldo's export
zone project is comparable
to my windmill project
during my time as mayor.
That's why I don't see any reason why
you'd refuse my grandson's offer.
[Arnaldo] Easy, Grandpa.
Ivy might think we have
an agenda for inviting her.
It's all right.
Um… Actually, Congressman…
I promised the Mayor I'd invest,
but, of course,
I still have to do my research.
And if everything looks fine,
I'll sign the agreement.
A woman with a very good head
on her shoulders.
A rare jewel.
Very… very… very rare.
It also helps you're a beautiful woman.
-Thank you, Mr. Congressman.
-[Julio chuckles]
[Julio] Oh. Right on time!
Now that we're done
talking about business…
we can enjoy dinner.
Ivy, do you like steak?
You know, if there's
one thing you should learn about
this whole family, it's that we love meat.
-[Ivy chuckles]
-What about you?
Kinda.
But it has to taste good.
[sensual music playing]
[Julio laughs]
[Julio] Touché.
-Hello.
-Good evening, sir!
[Ivy] You know, Congressman,
I think Mr. Mayor took after you.
A true visionary.
It runs in the blood.
Your grandsons took after you.
[Julio] If you're talking about Arnaldo,
then yes, he took after me.
I'm proud to say.
But didn't you introduce me
to your brother the other day?
-Where is he?
-[Julio] Well…
He's busy, very busy.
He's always busy with whatever he's doing.
Anyway, I don't see any way
how he can improve tonight's company.
Believe me, Ivy.
You're not missing anything.
You see, in every family…
there always has to be someone who's…
Um… How do you put it nicely?
-Weak.
-Dad.
[tense music playing]
[Julio] Uh…
Let's not talk about him.
But then, Arnaldo has more than made up…
for that boy's shortcomings.
And proof of that is you, my dear, Ivy.
You are here with us tonight
because of Arnaldo.
[tense music playing]
[grunts]
[grunting]
[Ivy] Your grandsons took after you.
[Julio] If you're talking
about Arnaldo, then yes.
[Ivy] But didn't you
introduce me to your brother
the other day?
[Julio] He's busy, very busy.
I don't see any way how he can
improve tonight's company.
You see, in every family…
there always has to be someone who's…
-[Diego grunts]
-[Julio] …weak.
[Diego grunting]
I won't allow you to go home by yourself.
I can drive you home.
If you insist, Mr. Mayor.
Okay. Let me get my keys.
Uh, wait. I think I need
to use the restroom.
Sure. This way.
Okay. Excuse me.
["Sa'Yo" instrumental playing]
I'm sorry.
I was looking for the restroom.
I opened the wrong door.
Sorry.
["Sa'Yo" by Silent Sanctuary playing]
Ivy, wait.
I've been thinking about this
since we met at the tournament.
You look familiar.
Have we met before?
["Sa'Yo" by Silent Sanctuary playing]
Hello, friends!
[Loring] I guess Ms. Ivy's one
of the governor's friends now.
I must've had the wrong impression of her.
Babe!
[Carlotta] You're looking
for justice, right?
It'll take you a while
before you find evidence.
But if you're after revenge,
it's as quick as one bullet.
Hello? I have a job for you.
The Ardiente family will be gone.
[man] Emilia Ardiente-Torillo!
Your days are over!
[theme music playing]